Subodh Kathayat

kathayatsubodh20@gmail.com| +977 9863202510| (8) Subodh Kathayat | LinkedIn

PROFILE

As an invested social worker, I am dedicated to improving the lives of underprivileged children and advocating for digital literacy. In addition to my passion for social work, I am also a skilled computer science researcher and programmer, with a strong entrepreneurial spirit. My diverse background and expertise allows me to approach problem-solving and innovation with a unique perspective.

EDUCATION:

Kathmandu Model Secondary School, Bagbazar, Kathmandu - +2 Science

GPA: 3.5/4.0 (N/A)

Radiant Montessori English Boarding School - SEE

GPA: 3.35/4.0 (Class rank: 5th out of 133 students)

SKILLS: Initiative Adaptive Passionate Research

Leadership Problem Solving Resiliency Programming

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE:

Asha Ka Paila Nepal-Co-founder

01/2020-Present

Graduation: 02/2021

Graduation: 06/2018

- Provided assistance to 150+ homeless families by collecting and distributing winter clothing during a community drive
- Partnered with local organizations to distribute essential items, including sanitizer, masks, and hygiene products, to homeless individuals in Tikapur during the COVID-19 pandemic
- Led a successful book drive that collected 3,000+ donations for the construction of a library in Tikapur, Kailali
- Distributed educational resources, including books and supplies, to disadvantaged children in Tikapur
- Contributed to the Save Siyona project by raising \$650 for a child diagnosed with Muscular Atrophy type-I
- Collaborated with the Tikapur Community Library to implement the "Green and Clean Tikapur" initiative
- Organized a campaign to promote digital education for all members of the community
- Developed the (आशाका पाईलाहर ् (aashakapaila.org) official website

Computer Science Club, Kathmandu Model College - Co-Founder and Lead Designer

08/2019 - 08/2020

- Chief Organizer of KMC Techno-fest, organized 11+ tech competitions (like RoboWar, Codeathon, RoboSoccer, etc.) managed sponsors, led team of 100+ students. 500+ participants from 110+ high schools from all over Nepal
- Organized free programming classes by partnering with popular tech companies like NeoSphere and LeapFrog
- Coordinated team preparation for various competitions, represented school in national and international competitions and hackathons

Neptechpal- UI/UX Designer/ Backend dev

08/2021 - 2023

- UI/UX Design: Strong experience in creating wireframes, prototypes, and high-fidelity mockups using tools such as Sketch,
 Figma, and Adobe Creative Suite.
- Backend Development: Proficient in Python framework Django and experienced in building REST APIs, managing database systems, and integrating third-party services.
- Published App: Successfully launched a published app with a seamless user experience and high user engagement.

Computer Science Basic and Diploma Courses -Teaching Assistant

12/2015 - 09/2016

- Basic and Diploma in Computer Science, Tikapur Community Library (2015) Topper of the batch, 250 students
- Taught basic computer skills to over 600+ students in Tikapur, Kailali, through a program organized by the Tikapur Community Library.
- Successfully organized and hosted 15-day coding camps for high school students, with over 100 participants.
- Planned and executed events related to computer science in schools located in remote areas, aimed at inspiring students to pursue careers in technology.

Far-western University I Research Assistant

02/2021 - 05/2021

- Conducted extensive research on types of maize in Sudurpaschim, including field visits to 13 locations and data collection from local farmers.
- Published research findings in the national Journal for Research in Agriculture Technology, with support from the World Bank.
- Computed and analyzed overall data and submitted after six complete months research with Professor. Lal Prasad Amgain,
 Dean, Far-western University.

Pokhara University I Assistant

02/2022 - 06/2022

- Teaching Assistant, C Programming and UI/UX Design: Assisted in the delivery of C programming and UI/UX design courses
 to first-year engineering students with non-coding backgrounds
- Conducted Workshops: Led workshops on various topics, including flutter, UI/UX, and C, for engineering students

IT officer, Leo Club of Silver Mountains

04/2022- Present

- Selected as official IT officer, responsible for the overall management of IT-related work,
- Led club projects in IT-related areas
- Photographed events and developed social media content
- Honored as Leo of the Month (September) for outstanding contributions to the organization

Nepal's Biggest Coding Olympics, Community Builder

11/2022- Present

- Selected as a community builder for Nepal's biggest coding Olympics, a national-level event for students in grades 4-10
- Led the registration process for participants and organized an on-city program using the Code Monkey platform
- Demonstrated leadership and program management skills in the successful delivery of the event.

Badminton Junior state level player and a trainer

2010 -Present

- · Participated in many junior badminton competitions
- Won 1st place in the junior state level badminton competition held in Dhangadhi, Kabadhall
- Winner of the Male double badminton competition held in Tikapur and honored as the youngest player
- Trained doctors during the pandemic and improved their badminton skills
- All-time high school sports week male badminton winner

Model United Nation I Participant

07/2020 - 05/2021

- Represented Bhutan in the Asia-World Model United Nation conference and discussed UNESCO's prompt education initiatives during the COVID-19 pandemic (Virtual-International)
- Honored with the Best Position Paper award at the Asia-World Model United Nation conference
- Represented the delegate of Zimbabwe in the Rotaract Pokhara University Model United Nation conference and focused on UNICEF initiatives (National)
- Participated in the Adarsha Model United Nation conference as a delegate of India, representing WHO, contributed to the
 drafting and passage of a resolution addressing the global shortage of healthcare workers. (National)

ROTA Projects I Restless Nepal I Participant

02/2019 - 04/2019

- Participated in a project organized by Restless Nepal at the Tikapur Community Library
- Developed leadership, life skills, public speaking, problem-solving skills, and soft skills through the completion of 20 assigned projects
- Contributed to the community through service learning and hands-on experience, gaining valuable practical experience while
 making a positive impact.

ONGOING PROJECTS:

Neptou App I Nepal Tourism Mobile Application I Founder

- Founder and Lead Developer of Nepal's First Official Tourism App
- Collaborated with the Nepal Tourism Board on the project
- Developed app focused on promoting tourism sector and local products, with a focus on providing employment opportunities for youth and targeting international tourists.

Code Olympics I Coding Olympics Nepal (CON) I Community Builder & Mentor

- Serving as a community builder for the national Code Olympics competition, on city Kathmandu area.
- Visited over 15 schools, spreading awareness of the importance of coding to junior and senior level students
- Leading the Gongabhu team and successfully raised registration for the competition
- Demonstrated strong communication and leadership skills in engaging with the community and promoting the event.

ACHIEVEMENTS / HONORS

- Winner of the Leo International Business Challenge (1st out of 74+ teams from Nepal, India, Bhutan, Mali) 2022
- 1st runner-up for the ICT award (500+ teams nominated in Nepal's biggest IT award, The rising star category) 2022

- Honored as Leo of the Month in the Leo Club of Silver Mountains (for the most impactful project completed) 2022
- Winner of the Hult Prize Competition (1st out of 39 teams from Pokhara University) 2022
- Youth for Tomorrow award: (Tikapur community library awarded for impactful social works) 2021
- Biggest National Hackathon "Codefest 2022" (3rd out of 90+ national teams, recognized as the youngest team) 2022
- Global Quiz Competition (Province 7 winner and selected as one of the top 7 teams from Nepal) 2021
- Winner of the Tikapur Male Badminton Championship (1st out of 67 teams, youngest player in the duo category) 2018
- Winner of the inter-college badminton competition: (Won the double male badminton competition at KMC) 2019
- Student of the Year: (Award for the most excellent, disciplined, and punctual student) 2016

SKILLS:

- Html/CSS/JS
- MS package
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Premiere pro
- C/C++ language
- UI/UX (Figma)
- Flutter
- Guitar
- Cinematography
- Photography
- Badminton
- Public Speaking